Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking all about animals.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊的全是关于动物的话题。
That's right.
没错。
This is a very interesting topic, very important because a lot of people like to have pets.
这是个很有趣的话题，也很重要，因为很多人喜欢养宠物。
That's right.
没错。
We're not going to the zoo.
我们不是要去动物园。
We're not talking about animals out in the forest or in nature.
我们不是聊森林里或大自然中的动物。
We're talking about pets that you keep at home.
我们聊的是你在家养的宠物。
So let's start right away with today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about
那我们就直接开始今天的对话，稍后回来再讨论
what's going on.
发生了什么。
We have been over this a hundred times.
这件事我们已经讨论过一百遍了。
We are not getting a pet.
我们不养宠物。
Why not?
为什么不养？
Come on.
拜托。
Just a cute little puppy or a kitty.
就一只可爱的小狗或小猫嘛。
Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
谁来照顾狗或猫？
I will.
我来。
I'll feed it, bathe it, and walk it every day.
我会喂它、给它洗澡、每天遛它。
We can get a Labrador or a German Shepherd.
我们可以养一只拉布拉多或德国牧羊犬。
What if we want to take a vacation?
那如果我们想去度假呢？
Who will we leave it with?
把它留给谁？
Our apartment is too small for that breed of dog.
我们的公寓太小了，养不了那种品种的狗。
Okay.
好吧。
How about we get a cat or a ferret?
那我们养只猫或雪貂怎么样？
We're planning on having children soon.
我们很快就要生孩子了。
I don't think those animals are a good idea with a baby in the house.
我觉得家里有宝宝的话，养那些动物不是好主意。
Fine.
行。
Let's get a bird then.
那养只鸟吧。
We can keep it in its cage and teach it to talk.
我们可以把它关在笼子里，教它说话。
A parrot would be awesome.
养只鹦鹉就太棒了。
I'll tell you what.
我跟你说。
I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it from there.
我可以给你买几只仓鼠，然后我们再看情况。
Yay!
耶！
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously pets, having a pet at home is a very big responsibility and well this is
很明显，宠物，在家养宠物是个很大的责任，而这正是
what the couple was talking about.
这对夫妻在讨论的。
But before we get into that discussion, why don't we take a look at five key words that
但在我们深入讨论之前，不如先看看我们为你们挑选的五个关键词，
we have picked out for you on Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So first off the couple is talking about whether they should get a dog or a cat or puppy or
首先，这对夫妻在讨论他们该养狗、猫、小狗还是
kitty and when they start talking about dogs, they talk about what kinds of dogs or the
小猫，当他们开始聊狗时，他们提到了狗的种类或
breed of the dogs.
狗的品种。
Let's look at this word.
我们来看看这个词。
That's right.
没错。
They were talking about a German Shepherd or a Labrador and as you said this is the
他们提到了德国牧羊犬或拉布拉多，正如你所说，这就是
breed or maybe you can say a kind of dog.
品种，或者你也可以说是一种狗。
That's right.
没错。
So breed is the technical word to describe the kind of dog that something is.
所以“breed”是描述某种狗种类的专业术语。
So like you said these are two examples.
就像你说的，这是两个例子。
There are many, many, many breeds that we can talk about but we'll just leave it at
我们可以聊很多很多品种，但我们就先
this for now.
说到这里。
But we talked about some other kinds of animals today.
但我们今天还聊了其他一些动物。
But we heard about some other kinds of animals today.
但我们今天还听到了其他一些动物。
Not dogs, not cats, maybe smaller animals.
不是狗，不是猫，可能是更小的动物。
That's right.
没错。
One of the animals that the person mentioned was a ferret.
其中一个人提到的一种动物是雪貂。
Oh a ferret.
哦，雪貂。
So this is a very small, kind of long animal.
这是一种非常小、身体有点长的动物。
That's right.
没错。
You may have seen it, pets before.
你可能见过它，以前有人养过。
They kind of look like, I don't know, kind of they have the face of a rat maybe but they're
它们看起来有点像，我不知道，可能脸像老鼠，但身体
very long.
很长。
And they're thin.
而且很瘦。
They're very thin.
它们非常瘦。
They're not like a rat because maybe their body shape is very, very different.
它们不像老鼠，因为体型非常非常不同。
But they're also kind of small and they like to eat those little insects.
但它们也还算小，喜欢吃那些小昆虫。
Yeah.
嗯。
I don't know if they have long tails like rats do.
我不知道它们是不是像老鼠一样有长尾巴。
I think they have furry tails.
我觉得它们有毛茸茸的尾巴。
I don't think their tails are different.
我不觉得它们的尾巴有什么不同。
Yeah.
嗯。
So that's a ferret.
那就是雪貂。
But we also heard about a special kind of bird.
但我们还听到了一种特殊的鸟。
That's right.
没错。
We talked about a parrot.
我们聊到了鹦鹉。
So as you know, there are many different kinds of birds.
如你所知，鸟有很多不同的种类。
You can see birds at your window all the time.
你随时都能在窗外看到鸟。
But birds that come from tropical places, usually very, very colorful birds are called
但来自热带地区的鸟，通常非常非常色彩鲜艳的鸟，被称为
parrots.
鹦鹉。
That's right.
没错。
So a parrot usually can talk or imitate what you say or sounds, right?
所以鹦鹉通常能说话或模仿你说的话或声音，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're actually very famous in the bird world for having a good ability to reproduce or
它们在鸟类世界中以擅长复制或
to mimic the sounds that you make.
模仿你发出的声音而闻名。
So if I say, hello, my parrot says, hello.
所以如果我说“你好”，我的鹦鹉就会说“你好”。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
It's really strange.
这真的很奇怪。
They're very, very intelligent animals.
它们是非常非常聪明的动物。
So that's a parrot.
那就是鹦鹉。
And our last animal is a very small animal, very popular also to have as a pet.
而我们最后一种动物是一种非常小的动物，也很受欢迎作为宠物。
We talked about a hamster.
我们提到了仓鼠。
A hamster.
仓鼠。
So this is a little bit like a mouse.
这有点像老鼠。
They're furry.
它们有毛。
They're small.
它们很小。
They're round.
它们圆滚滚的。
And they live in glass cages or fish tanks, usually.
它们通常住在玻璃笼子或鱼缸里。
Yeah.
是的。
They're very small.
它们非常小。
They don't really do much.
它们不怎么活动。
They're just little furry creatures and they, I don't know, they just eat all day.
它们就是些毛茸茸的小生物，而且，我不知道，它们整天就是吃。
Sometimes they get those little wheels that they can get inside and run around all day.
有时候它们会有那种小轮子，可以钻进去整天跑。
That's right.
没错。
Or when I was a child and we had a hamster, we had a special plastic ball.
或者我小时候养仓鼠时，我们有一个特别的塑料球。
And you put the hamster in the ball and he would go around the house.
你把仓鼠放进球里，它就会在房子里到处跑。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
It's very fun.
这很有趣。
All right.
好了。
So we took a look at the pets that you can buy, domestic animals.
所以我们看了你可以买的宠物，家养动物。
But taking a look at something very specific, when they were describing the responsibilities
但具体来看，当他们描述养狗或养猫的责任时，
of having maybe a dog or a cat, they said they have to feed it, bathe it, walk it.
他们说要喂它、给它洗澡、遛它。
So obviously we know that feed it is to give it food.
所以显然我们知道“喂它”就是给它食物。
But what about bathe it?
但“给它洗澡”呢？
Okay.
好的。
So you might know the word bath.
你可能知道“bath”这个词。
Okay.
好的。
That's a thing.
那是一个东西。
It's a noun.
它是名词。
Bathe is a verb.
“Bathe”是动词。
To bathe.
洗澡。
And so I can bathe myself.
所以我可以给自己洗澡。
That means I take a shower.
那意味着我淋浴。
I clean my body.
我清洁身体。
Or I can bathe something else, like an animal.
或者我可以给别的东西洗澡，比如动物。
So bathing a dog means basically washing a dog.
所以给狗洗澡基本上就是洗狗。
Right.
对。
So it sounds very fancy or formal if you say, I'm going to go take a shower.
所以如果你说“我要去淋浴”，听起来很花哨或正式。
Or you say, I'm going to go bathe.
或者你说“我要去洗澡”。
Yeah.
是的。
We don't really say that as much.
我们其实不常那么说。
But we often say bathe when we're talking about cleaning other things.
但当我们谈论清洁其他东西时，我们经常说“bathe”。
Not a table, but cleaning people or animals.
不是桌子，而是清洁人或动物。
Right.
对。
So you can say, did you bathe the baby?
所以你可以说“你给婴儿洗澡了吗？”
Or did you bathe the dog?
或者“你给狗洗澡了吗？”
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
And also remember that even though the dog may be female or male, we don't give it gender.
还要记住，即使狗可能是雌性或雄性，我们也不给它赋予性别。
Right?
对吧？
We describe it as it.
我们用“它”来描述。
That's right.
没错。
Animals are almost always considered it in English.
在英语中，动物几乎总是被视为“它”。
Although some people who really love their animals call it he or she.
尽管有些非常爱动物的人会叫它“他”或“她”。
Right.
对。
So it's kind of your decision.
所以这有点取决于你的决定。
It's not really incorrect if you say, oh, my dog, she's so beautiful, if it's a female.
如果你说“哦，我的狗，她真漂亮”，如果它是雌性，这并不算错。
But technically, you should say, my dog, it's very beautiful.
但严格来说，你应该说“我的狗，它很漂亮”。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of words there.
所以我们看了很多词汇。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue, and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回去听一下对话，一会儿再回来。
We have been over this a hundred times.
我们已经讨论过一百遍了。
We are not getting a pet.
我们不养宠物。
Why not?
为什么不呢？
Come on.
拜托了。
Just a cute little puppy or kitty.
就一只可爱的小狗或小猫。
Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
谁来照顾狗或猫呢？
I will.
我来。
I'll feed it, bathe it, and walk it every day.
我会每天喂它、给它洗澡、带它散步。
We can get a Labrador or a German Shepherd.
我们可以养一只拉布拉多或德国牧羊犬。
What if we want to take a vacation?
如果我们想去度假怎么办？
Who will we leave it with?
我们把它留给谁呢？
Plus, our apartment is too small for that breed of dog.
而且，我们的公寓对于那种狗来说太小了。
Okay.
好吧。
How about we get a cat or a ferret?
那我们养只猫或雪貂怎么样？
We're planning on having children soon.
我们很快就要孩子了。
I don't think those animals are a good idea with a baby in the house.
我觉得家里有宝宝的话，养那些动物不太合适。
Fine.
行吧。
Let's get a bird then.
那我们就养只鸟吧。
We can keep it in its cage and teach it to talk.
我们可以把它关在笼子里，教它说话。
A parrot would be awesome.
养只鹦鹉会很酷。
I'll tell you what.
我跟你说吧。
I can get you some hamsters, and we'll take it from there.
我可以给你买几只仓鼠，然后我们再慢慢来。
Yay!
耶！
All right.
好吧。
We're back.
我们回来了。
We've picked out four key phrases for you.
我们为你挑选了四个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those now in Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在流利度训练中看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
So at the very beginning of today's conversation, we hear the first person say, we've been over
所以在今天对话的开头，我们听到第一个人说，“我们讨论过”
this a hundred times.
这件事一百遍了。
So what does this mean?
那么这是什么意思呢？
This means that they've never talked about this before?
这是说他们以前从没讨论过这件事吗？
No, this is actually the opposite, but it's a way to exaggerate, right?
不，实际上恰恰相反，但这是一种夸张的说法，对吧？
Because obviously they haven't maybe talked about getting a pet a hundred times, but you're
因为显然他们可能没有真的讨论过养宠物一百次，但你
just making emphasis on the fact that we've talked about this many, many, many times.
只是在强调我们讨论过很多很多次这个事实。
And almost like you're tired of it.
而且几乎像是你对此感到厌烦了。
Like, oh, do we have to talk about this again?
就像，哦，我们非得再谈这个吗？
It's like you said, an exaggeration to say, come on.
就像你说的，是一种夸张，意思是“拜托”。
So we've been over this a million times.
所以我们讨论过这件事一百万遍了。
We've been over this a hundred times.
我们讨论过这件事一百遍了。
These are all ways of saying, oh, we have to talk about this again?
这些都是表达“哦，我们还得再谈这个吗？”的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
So you're emphasizing that, well, maybe you've done it too many times already.
所以你在强调，嗯，也许你已经做过太多次了。
All right.
好的。
And well, when they were talking about the puppy or the kitty, the guy asked, well, who's
嗯，当他们谈论小狗或小猫时，那个男的问，“那谁来”
going to look after the dog or the cat?
照顾狗或猫呢？
Okay.
好的。
So this is an important phrase.
所以这是一个重要的短语。
We're going to treat this as a kind of a chunk.
我们要把它当作一个整体来对待。
These words go together, to look after.
这些词是连在一起的，“to look after”。
So we could look after a baby or look after the pet.
所以我们可以说照顾婴儿或照顾宠物。
This means to watch or to care for.
这意味着照看或照料。
Right.
对。
To take care.
照顾。
So maybe if you're going to go out tonight, you want to leave your son with a babysitter
所以如果你今晚要出去，你可能想把儿子留给保姆
to look after him.
来照看他。
Right.
对。
To make sure that there are no problems or to make sure that he eats and goes to sleep.
确保没有麻烦，或者确保他吃饭和睡觉。
Exactly.
没错。
So to look after, to take care or to make sure he or she is okay.
所以“to look after”就是照顾或确保他或她没事。
All right.
好的。
And well, obviously the guy didn't want a puppy.
显然，那个家伙不想要小狗。
He didn't want a kitty.
他不想要小猫。
So the girl was giving alternatives and said, well, how about we get a cat or a ferret?
所以女孩在提供替代方案，说，那我们养只猫或雪貂怎么样？
Okay.
好的。
The phrase here, how about, is very, very common in English.
这里的短语“how about”在英语中非常非常常见。
I think a lot of people who learn English have a hard time knowing when to use this
我觉得很多学英语的人很难知道什么时候用这个。
phrase.
短语。
How about?
怎么样？
That's right.
没错。
So it's very simple.
所以这很简单。
The phrase how about is to give an alternative.
短语“怎么样”是用来提出一个替代方案。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Or a suggestion.
或者一个建议。
So for example, you and I are talking about where to eat lunch.
比如，你和我正在讨论去哪里吃午饭。
I don't know.
我不知道。
And you give a suggestion.
然后你提出一个建议。
You say, how about pizza?
你说，吃披萨怎么样？
And I say, I don't know.
然后我说，我不知道。
How about McDonald's?
吃麦当劳怎么样？
We're giving suggestions or offering alternatives.
我们在提出建议或提供替代方案。
Exactly.
正是。
So this is the correct way of using how about.
所以这是使用“怎么样”的正确方式。
Many students make the mistake of using it as to say, how was it?
很多学生会犯错误，把它用成“它怎么样？”。
Or how did it go?
或者“进行得怎么样？”。
Right?
对吧？
Right.
没错。
So how was your weekend?
那你周末过得怎么样？
That's correct.
这就对了。
How about your weekend?
你周末怎么样？
That's incorrect.
那不对。
No, do not say that.
不，别那么说。
You want to say, how about this?
你应该说，这个怎么样？
How about that?
那个怎么样？
How about a Coke?
来杯可乐怎么样？
How about some food?
来点吃的怎么样？
These are suggestions, but a real question you have to say how was or how is.
这些是建议，但真正的问句你得说“how was”或“how is”。
Right.
没错。
So never, never, never say, how about your weekend?
所以永远、永远、永远别说“how about your weekend？”
That is incorrect.
那是不对的。
And it's actually very common to hear this from students.
而且实际上经常听到学生这么说。
So remember, it's not correct.
所以记住，那是不正确的。
How about your weekend?
你周末怎么样？
No, incorrect.
不，不对。
So at the very end of the dialogue, we're talking about hamsters.
在对话的最后，我们谈到了仓鼠。
I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it from there.
我可以给你弄几只仓鼠，然后我们再看情况。
That's right.
没错。
The phrase take it from there.
短语“take it from there”。
It's kind of a way of saying, look, let's start with something small or let's start
这有点像在说，看，我们先从小事开始，或者从简单的事开始，
with something simple and we will see how it goes.
然后看看进展如何。
So basically the woman is saying, I don't want to commit.
所以基本上那个女人在说，我不想承诺。
I don't want to agree to get a big animal like a dog or a cat because I'm not sure how
我不想同意养像狗或猫这样的大动物，因为我不确定
it will be.
会是什么情况。
I'm not sure if it will be too much responsibility.
我不确定责任会不会太大。
So she's saying, okay, we'll get something small and then we'll wait and we'll see what
所以她说，好吧，我们先养个小东西，然后等等看
happens.
会发生什么。
We'll take it from there.
我们再看情况。
That's right.
没错。
So it's basically saying, let's start slowly.
所以这基本上就是说，我们慢慢开始。
So for example, maybe a guy asks you out and says, hey, will you marry me?
比如，也许一个男的约你出去，说，嘿，你愿意嫁给我吗？
And you say, whoa.
然后你说，哇。
Let's go on a date first and we'll take it from there.
我们先约会一次，然后再说。
Exactly.
正是。
We'll see what happens.
我们看看会发生什么。
So let's start slowly.
所以我们慢慢来。
Let's take things step by step.
我们一步一步来。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the phrases that we have for you today.
这就是我们今天为你准备的所有短语。
I think we should listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little
我觉得我们应该再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊
bit more.
一点。
We've been over this a hundred times.
这事我们已经讨论过一百遍了。
We are not getting a pet.
我们不养宠物。
Why not?
为什么不？
Come on.
拜托。
Just a cute little puppy or kitty.
就一只可爱的小狗或小猫。
Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
谁来照顾狗或猫？
I will.
我来。
I'll feed it, bathe it and walk it every day.
我会喂它、给它洗澡、每天遛它。
We can get a Labrador or a German shepherd.
我们可以养一只拉布拉多或德国牧羊犬。
What if we want to take a vacation?
如果我们想去度假怎么办？
Who will we leave it with?
我们把它留给谁？
Plus, our apartment is too small for that breed of dog.
而且，我们的公寓对于那种狗来说太小了。
Okay.
好吧。
How about we get a cat or a ferret?
那我们养只猫或雪貂怎么样？
We're planning on having children soon.
我们很快就要孩子了。
I don't think those animals are a good idea with a baby in the house.
我觉得家里有宝宝的话，养那些动物不是好主意。
Fine.
好吧。
Let's get a bird then.
那我们就养只鸟吧。
We can keep it in its cage and teach it to talk.
我们可以把它关在笼子里，教它说话。
A parrot would be awesome.
养只鹦鹉会很棒。
I'll tell you what.
我跟你说吧。
I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it from there.
我可以给你弄几只仓鼠，然后我们再看情况。
Yay!
耶！
Alright Catherine, so what about pets?
好了，凯瑟琳，那宠物呢？
Are you a big pet lover?
你是个宠物爱好者吗？
Do you like ferrets, hamsters, all this good stuff?
你喜欢雪貂、仓鼠这些好东西吗？
I don't like small pets.
我不喜欢小宠物。
I love big pets.
我喜欢大宠物。
So as a kid we had both.
小时候我们两种都养过。
My brother really loved small animals like hamsters and ferrets and things like that.
我哥哥真的很喜欢小动物，比如仓鼠、雪貂之类的。
I just think they're a little bit stinky.
我只是觉得它们有点臭。
They kind of smell funny.
它们闻起来怪怪的。
So ever since, I've always really liked big animals like dogs.
从那以后，我一直很喜欢像狗这样的大动物。
So you are a dog person.
所以你是个爱狗的人。
I am a dog person.
我是个爱狗的人。
This is something interesting that we describe in English.
这是我们在英语中描述的一个有趣现象。
People say I am a dog person.
人们说我是一个爱狗的人。
I am a cat person.
我是一个爱猫的人。
It's almost like it says something about your personality.
这几乎像是在说你的性格。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you're a dog person, it means that you prefer dogs or you like dogs.
所以如果你是一个爱狗的人，意思是你更喜欢狗或喜欢狗。
If you're a cat person, you prefer cats.
如果你是一个爱猫的人，你更喜欢猫。
And a lot of people really like dogs but don't really like cats or they love cats and they
很多人真的很喜欢狗，但不太喜欢猫，或者他们爱猫却
can't stand dogs.
受不了狗。
Right.
对。
And it even gets to the point where I've heard that maybe on dates people will ask, so are
甚至到了我听说在约会时人们会问，那么你是
you a dog person or a cat person?
爱狗的人还是爱猫的人？
I know that's how I pick dates.
我知道我就是这样挑选约会对象的。
Really?
真的吗？
What about you?
你呢？
Are you a dog person or a cat person?
你是爱狗的人还是爱猫的人？
I'm definitely a dog person.
我绝对是爱狗的人。
Good answer.
好答案。
Yeah.
嗯。
I think cats are, I mean they're nice and they're cuddly and I think they're very good
我觉得猫，它们很可爱，也很抱抱，而且我认为它们是很好的
indoor pets and a little bit more fun than maybe a hamster.
室内宠物，比仓鼠稍微有趣一点。
But I think dogs have more life and are more energetic.
但我认为狗更有活力，更有精力。
I think cats are very lazy.
我觉得猫很懒。
And I think sometimes cats like to play mind games.
而且我觉得有时候猫喜欢玩心理游戏。
Like they're so smart that they can control you.
比如它们太聪明了，能控制你。
That makes me uncomfortable.
这让我不舒服。
All right.
好吧。
So, well, there are a lot of other pets out there.
那么，还有很多其他宠物。
Some people have tarantula, some people have iguanas, other people have fish.
有些人养狼蛛，有些人养鬣蜥，其他人养鱼。
Or horses.
或者马。
Horses.
马。
If you have enough space, right?
如果你有足够空间，对吧？
So we want to know what kind of pets do you have or did you have as a kid?
所以我们想知道你养什么宠物，或者小时候养过什么？
That's right.
没错。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好吧。
Bye.
再见。